<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>jaffamonkey</title>
    <subtitle>jaffamonkey is a professional Quality Engineer based in Kent, UK.</subtitle>
    <link href="https://jaffamonkey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
    <link href="https://jaffamonkey.com" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
        <name>jaffamonkey</name>
    </author>
    
    <updated>2024-05-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    
    <id>https://jaffamonkey.com/</id>
        <entry>
            <title>Quality Engineering</title>
            <link href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/quality-engineering/"/>
            <updated>2024-05-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <id>https://jaffamonkey.com/services/quality-engineering/</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
                <p class="lead">Bringing quality to all aspects of a project, bringing quality assurance and testing to the SDLC, from design to production.</p>
<div class="callout callout--tip"><span class="callout__icon"><svg class="icon icon--lightbulb" role="img" aria-hidden="true" width="24" height="24"><use xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="/assets/icons/icons.sprite.svg#icon-lightbulb"></use></svg></span><div class="callout__content"><p>If you are trying to &quot;shift left, I can help bring testing earlier and more frequently, into the design and development cycles.</p></div></div>
<p>Firstly I develop adaptive test strategies for applying quality checks from design through to development. At the core of the implementation are lean UI and API test frameworks, integrated into CI/CD pipelines. Along with performance tests with every build to check accessibility, load and security.</p>
<h2 id="h-our-focus"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/quality-engineering/#h-our-focus" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Our focus</h2>
<ul>
<li>Adaptive test strategies.</li>
<li>Applying quality checks from design through to development.</li>
<li>UI test frameworks to do richer tests, focused on UX.</li>
<li>API test frameworks with service virtulisation to ensure test continuity.</li>
<li>Performance tests with every build to check Accessibility, Load and Security.</li>
<li>Integrating testing into CI/CD pipelines as early as possible.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://calendly.com/jaffamonkeyltd/intro-call" class="btn btn--primary" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Book a meeting</a></p>

            ]]></content>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>Accessibility Strategy</title>
            <link href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-strategy/"/>
            <updated>2024-05-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <id>https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-strategy/</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
                <div class="callout callout--tip"><span class="callout__icon"><svg class="icon icon--lightbulb" role="img" aria-hidden="true" width="24" height="24"><use xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="/assets/icons/icons.sprite.svg#icon-lightbulb"></use></svg></span><div class="callout__content"><p>Understanding why accessibility makes you a better and smarter organisation is the first step in any long-term strategy.</p></div></div>
<p>Define accessibility goals and requirements at the outset, with an Accessibility strategy. This includes understanding legal obligations and setting clear objectives for compliance with the <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG22/">Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG 2.2)</a>. This will set out the clear aims of how Accessibility will be included in each phase of app development.</p>
<h2 id="h-why-do-a-strategy%3F"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-strategy/#h-why-do-a-strategy%3F" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Why do a strategy?</h2>
<h3 id="h-drive-innovation"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-strategy/#h-drive-innovation" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Drive Innovation</h3>
<p>Accessibility features in products and services often solve unanticipated problems.</p>
<h3 id="h-enhance-your-brand"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-strategy/#h-enhance-your-brand" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Enhance Your Brand</h3>
<p>Diversity and inclusion efforts so important to business success are accelerated with a clear, well-integrated accessibility commitment.</p>
<h3 id="h-extend-market-reach"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-strategy/#h-extend-market-reach" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Extend Market Reach</h3>
<p>The global market of people with disabilities is over 1 billion people with a spending power of more than $6 trillion. Accessibility often improves the online experience for all users.</p>
<h3 id="h-minimize-legal-risk"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-strategy/#h-minimize-legal-risk" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Minimize Legal Risk</h3>
<p>Many countries have laws requiring digital accessibility, and the issue is of increased legal concern.</p>
<p><a href="https://calendly.com/jaffamonkeyltd/intro-call" class="btn btn--primary" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Book a meeting</a></p>

            ]]></content>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>Accessibility Audit</title>
            <link href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/"/>
            <updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <id>https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
                <p class="lead">The purpose of an Accessibility Audit is to establish how well a website or mobile app performs in terms of access and ease of use by a wide range of potential users, including people with disabilities and the visually impaired. Part of audit is also to recommend improvements, where necessary.</p>
<div class="callout callout--tip"><span class="callout__icon"><svg class="icon icon--lightbulb" role="img" aria-hidden="true" width="24" height="24"><use xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="/assets/icons/icons.sprite.svg#icon-lightbulb"></use></svg></span><div class="callout__content"><p>Get an audit at any point in your project, and also get advice with pushing accessibility as part of your way of working, from design to code to production.</p></div></div>
<h1>Accessibility Standards</h1>
<p>W3C specified the <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG22/">Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG 2.2)</a> success criteria for Accessibility compliance. Following these guidelines will provide greater accessibility to a wider range of people with disabilities, across a range of devices (desktops, laptops, tablets and smartphones).</p>
<p>For mobile apps, <a href="https://developer.apple.com/design/human-interface-guidelines/accessibility">Apple’s Human Interface Guidelines</a> and <a href="https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui/accessibility">Android’s Accessibility Principles</a>, should also be taken into consideration.</p>
<h2 id="h-summary"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/#h-summary" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Summary</h2>
<p>The audit targets a wide range of disabilities, including visual, auditory, physical, speech, cognitive, language, learning, and neurological disabilities. Professionally evaluating the website’s accessibility level is a key step in web accessibility and can be performed at any stage of a web or mobile app project.</p>
<h2 id="h-advantages"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/#h-advantages" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Advantages</h2>
<p>Our services are cost-effective and efficient, ensuring that businesses of all sizes can afford and benefit from our expertise. Our in-depth knowledge and experience in Accessibility and WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines) compliance, allow us to deliver exceptional results and ensure that our clients’ digital content is accessible to all users.</p>
<p>Furthermore, our focus on DevOps integration is a unique aspect of our consultancy services. This integration of accessibility practices into the development workflow gives our clients a significant advantage in creating inclusive digital experiences.</p>
<h3 id="h-key-benefits"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/#h-key-benefits" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Key Benefits</h3>
<ul>
<li>Inclusivity: Integrating accessibility ensures that digital products are usable by a wider audience, including individuals with disabilities.</li>
<li>Legal Compliance: Adhering to accessibility standards like the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) helps avoid legal repercussions associated with non-compliance.</li>
<li>Improved User Experience: Accessible design often leads to better overall usability, benefiting all users, not just those with disabilities.</li>
<li>Business Advantages: A broader audience and enhanced user satisfaction can translate into increased engagement and customer loyalty.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="h-what-you-will-get"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/#h-what-you-will-get" aria-hidden="true">#</a> What you will get</h2>
<ul>
<li>A full accessibility review and test of web or mobile app against the WCAG 2.2 AA standard.</li>
<li>Delivery of a full, prioritised accessibility report of web and/or mobile app</li>
<li>Feedback on UX as well as UI issues.</li>
<li>An accessibility statement advising on status of WCAG 2.2 AA compliance.</li>
<li>Automated accessibility test framework(s) for your design and development cycles.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Optional extra is devising a strategy, to aimed at integrating Accessibility checks as part of design and development cycles.</em></p>
<div class="callout callout--tip"><span class="callout__icon"><svg class="icon icon--lightbulb" role="img" aria-hidden="true" width="24" height="24"><use xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="/assets/icons/icons.sprite.svg#icon-lightbulb"></use></svg></span><div class="callout__content"><p>Treat an audit as a startpoint, to integrating accessibility checks earlier in the development lifecycle.</p></div></div>
<h2 id="h-recent-audits"><a class="heading-anchor" href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/#h-recent-audits" aria-hidden="true">#</a> Recent audits</h2>
<ul>
<li>Coloplast</li>
<li>HealthwaveHub</li>
<li>Infervision</li>
<li>TympaHealth</li>
<li>ZoomDoc</li>
<li>Medialogix</li>
<li>IMS Maxims</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://calendly.com/jaffamonkeyltd/intro-call" class="btn btn--primary" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Book a meeting</a></p>

            ]]></content>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>Partner with us</title>
            <link href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/partner-with-us/"/>
            <updated>2024-05-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <id>https://jaffamonkey.com/services/partner-with-us/</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
                <p>I provide Accessibility Audit and related services to compliance companies, looking to fill Accessibility requirements in their overall compliance service.<br />
.</p>
<div class="callout callout--tip"><span class="callout__icon"><svg class="icon icon--lightbulb" role="img" aria-hidden="true" width="24" height="24"><use xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="/assets/icons/icons.sprite.svg#icon-lightbulb"></use></svg></span><div class="callout__content"><p>I am very flexible, can accommodate tight dealines, and can guarantee a maximum of 3 days lead-time, per platform under test (iOS/Android/Windows/Mac)</p></div></div>
<p><a href="https://jaffamonkey.com/services/accessibility-audit/">View the Accessibility service</a></p>

            ]]></content>
        </entry></feed>
